

#### Web • C# • Developer

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn

### **Background**

I am a 29-year-old software engineer based in Norwich. My preferred language is **C#** although I also have experience with **TypeScript**.

I have also started to take an interest in **F#** and functional paradigms. I have written an in-depth article introducing C# developers to F# that you can find <a href="here">here</a>. I also have experience with the Actor model via **Akka.NET**. My love for TDD and the Actor model lead me to write an Akka.NET unit test framework that you can find <a href="here">here</a>.

My hobbies include playing football and table tennis. I am a Newcastle United fan.

# **Experience**

#### **Applications Developer** Aviva

Apr 2018 – Present

During this role I predominantly worked on an existing greenfield project, aimed at minimising duplication amongst various code bases within the business. Upon my arrival I quickly provided value by improving the stability of the unit tests for the solution. Whilst working on the project I became a tech lead and I oversee a small number of offshore developers. The project uses **Akka.NET** for its backend and **SignalR** to update a React.JS SPA. I feel my knowledge of Akka.NET has been very valuable to the team.

During my time at Aviva I also developed a simple service virtualisation tool that we use as an alternative to LISA/Dev Test. This was written in **TypeScript** and was built using **Node.JS**.

#### **Applications Developer** Modality Systems

Feb 2015 - Mar 2018

During this role I worked on various solutions built around **Skype For Business**. I helped the dev team build out release pipelines in **VSTS** and embrace TDD & testing automation. This involved a large mentality shift with regards to how QA was approached. We tried to involve our testers as early as possible with each user story. I particularly enjoyed embracing TDD.

I led the design of one project that involved the co-ordinating of over 50 machines. It used **Akka.NET** and **SignalR** to achieve the distributed computing required. The machines could be configured using an **Angular2 TypeScript** web application. During this project we hired a junior dev whom I mentored which was an extremely rewarding experience. I was also stand-in scrum master for this project. I was involved in various Microsoft TAP programs during my time in this role which was very interesting.



# Web • C# • Developer

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn

#### **Applications Developer** C A Design Services

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

This was my first development role. I initially performed small support tasks and developed inhouse .NET solutions. I then moved on to developing enhancements and bug fixes to existing products. These systems were usually 3-tier ASP.NET Web Form Applications with T-SQL databases. I eventually began working on new projects and was the first person at the company to make a website using an ORM back-end (Entity Framework) and the MVC design pattern (ASP.NET MVC). My first project was for the large retail firm Sainsbury's. I also began writing unit tests for the first time during my time at C A Design Services.

				ons
	ша	Ca	<b>†</b> 1 <i>C</i>	nne
~		 Ca	UIV	,,,,,

onversity of Last Anglia 2010 2015	<b>BSc Hons in Software Engine</b>	ring Universi	ity of East Anglia 2010 – 2013
------------------------------------	------------------------------------	---------------	--------------------------------

2:2

### BTEC National Diploma in ICT Great Yarmouth College 2008 – 2010

Triple distinction

GCSEs Cliff Park High School 2002 – 2006

Grade A: English Language Grade B: English Literature

Grade C: Science × 2, Maths, Statistics, ICT, Electronics, Art, PE, RE